Contact

+91 8886001325 (Mobile) krishna.yvs@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ krishnayellapragada (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Technical Program Management
Delivery and Account Management
Quality Engineering

Krishna Yellapragada

Vice President Technology at Feuji Inc Hyderabad

Summary

Technology leader with an experience managing large engineering teams (Development, Quality Engineering) delivering high performance and quality products. Demonstrated experience in operations, people, program management and working with product, marketing, sales to achieve customer satisfaction.

Experience

Feuji Inc

1 year 10 months

Vice President Information Technology July 2021 - Present (9 months) India

I am currently heading the Digital Engineering Practice and Solution Engineering teams. Responsible for setting up Quality Engineering Practice, Low code / No Code Practice, Account management, and Mining. Build and implement. Hiring large teams across India/CR and responsible for the retention, Improving the team's happiness index and tech capabilities. Responsible for providing inputs to the organization and technical strategy to meet the business goals.

Director Of Engineering

June 2020 - December 2021 (1 year 7 months)

Hyderabad, Telangana, India

Leading engineering teams responsible for the Delivery, Technology, Solutions and Customer Satisfaction.

Wavelabs Technologies
AVP, Global Delivery
June 2018 - June 2020 (2 years 1 month)

Hyderabad, Telangana, India

Responsible for managing the Engineering, Technical Delivery and Account Management of the product engineering division of the organisation. Handling Client Relationship(Customer Satisfaction),Operational excellence(P &

L , team skill improvement, Resource Management, Hiring) and Business Growth(account mining). Setup high performing Quality Engineering Team(Test Automation, DevOPS, Presales) .

Worked with more than 10 product organisations in the capacity of engineering director

Set up TCOE in multiple product and enterprise organisations.

Closely worked with Client product management, Technology vendors and Partners to coordinate and integrate the feature development, work schedules and work monitoring

Implemented measures to optimise the unutilised cost Supported Sales and presales team to win new business

Cigniti Technologies 3 years 11 months

Associate Director - Global Delivery January 2017 - June 2018 (1 year 6 months) hyderabad

Independent Software Testing Organisation:

As a Delivery Director managed AUS, NZ, ME and SEA regions
Responsible for the Technical Delivery(Functional and Automation), Account
Management(Mining of accounts), Pre Sales Support(Tech Solutions), Sales
Support and Operational Excellence(profitability, process compliance)

Instrumental in building all 4 regions from ground up to 200 strong technical team

Established technical teams to build POC's, enhancing existing automation frameworks

Worked with more than 60+ clients across the regions
Reviewed the frameworks created and provided the feedback
Upskill and cross skill of team to support team professional growth and future organisation business

Sr.Manager - Global Delivery August 2014 - December 2016 (2 years 5 months) Hyderabad Area, India

Experienced in running large QA transformation Programs with the desired business outcomes and benefits. Handled multiple automation engagements across domains/tools/languages. Coordinated performance testing efforts across regions .Supported Sales and pre sales in winning the new business.

Tata Consultancy Services

9 years

Account Manager

January 2013 - August 2014 (1 year 8 months)

Hyderabad

Built and expanded the relationship with a large product organisation across India and US. Responsible for the Sales, Delivery and Client relationship.

Increased the revenue by 5X in an span of 1.5 years with an overall team size of 150 across India and US

Hosted client leadership team in TCS and showcased the capabilities across Digital and Analytics

Worked with Client leadership in Product Engineering, IT and IT Infrastructure teams.

Facilitated / Conducted workshops in Client premises on Application Modernisation for mainframe applications, Analytics(Project Management, Warranty etc.,)

Worked with internal stakeholders like RMG/TAG, Finance, PMO, Bid management and Legal

Experience in Handling managed services projects in a highly agile environment

Program Test Manager

April 2010 - December 2012 (2 years 9 months)

Handled end to end distributed product automation of 5k test cases across Web and API

Worked with Client QA teams, Release management team, Product team to define the outcomes and benefits of the program

Established Metrics and Measurement framework and reported the status of the KPI in regular intervals.

Coordinated with client release management team to align the deliverables as per product release schedule for getting maximum ROI

Involved in the business reviews with client leadership and worked on the changes suggested

Reviewed the benefits generated from the automated scripts and worked on the feedback

Resources Manager

December 2009 - March 2010 (4 months)

Hyderabad Area, India

Point of contact for all the resource needs of TCS - Microsoft relationship. Worked with internal stakeholders to gather the requirements and based of resource allocations, map them to right projects based on the priority. Worked with TAG and RMG for quick fulfilment, planned contract hiring/full time hiring drives across India.

Successfully Fulfilled 180+ open requirements

Conducted 50+ interview drives across India and worked with Vendors for quick fulfilment

Identified internal resources (Current and Future Bench) and cross trained on the required skills.

Project Manager

December 2008 - November 2009 (1 year)

Hyderabad, Telangana

Successfully executed managed services engagements in TCS-Microsoft relationship

Closely worked with procurement business team to derive the requirements Directed development and testing team worked on Microsoft technologies

Senior Software Development Engineer Test April 2008 - November 2008 (8 months)

United States

Worked as an SDET in Sharepoint practices and practices. Contributed to Sharepoint 2010 patterns and practices book release.

SE in EPP

September 2005 - March 2008 (2 years 7 months)

Goose Technologies. Hyderabad Software Developer 2004 - June 2005 (1 year)

Microsoft Backend developer responsible for developing business logic Worked on a product named "PROCON"

Conducted product demo's to prospects

Worked on customising product for new clients

Sree Sharada Infotech Software Developer May 2002 - June 2004 (2 years 2 months)

Software Developer worked on VB and VB.NET applications

Education

MRPG College, Vizianagaram Masters, Computers · (2000 - 2002)